Guide to the William R. Perl papers, 1925-1998 MS2026
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Jewish activism files, 1930-1990; MS2026 Series 2; 1 Linear foot
  - Correspondence: Mathias, Charles McC., 1973 September 07 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence: Meljon, Z., 1967 April 02 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence: Pienaker, David, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence: Steinberger, E.J., 1964 June 29 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Press Releases, Pamphlets and Broadsides: America-Israel Friendship League, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Press Releases, Pamphlets and Broadsides: American Jewish Historical Society, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Press Releases, Pamphlets and Broadsides: Americans Fighting Arab Blackmail, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Press Releases, Pamphlets and Broadsides: American Jews Against Ford, undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Press Releases, Pamphlets and Broadsides: American League for a Secure Israel, undated (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Press Releases, Pamphlets and Broadsides: Americans for a Safe Israel, undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Press Releases, Pamphlets and Broadsides: Embassy of Israel, undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Press Releases, Pamphlets and Broadsides: Jewish Defense League, 1969-1974 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Press Releases, Pamphlets and Broadsides: Jewish Nation Military Organisation of Erez Jisrael, undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Press Releases, Pamphlets and Broadsides: New Washington Committee for the Prevention of Genocide, undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Press Releases, Pamphlets and Broadsides: Tagar Zionist Student Activist Movement, undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Press Releases, Pamphlets and Broadsides: Washington Committee for Soviet Jewry, undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Press Releases, Pamphlets and Broadsides: unattributed, undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Awards and Honors: Jabotinsky Centennial Medal, The Jabotinsky Foundation, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Awards and Honors: Israel Achievement Award, Silver Spring Jewish Center, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Awards and Honors: Tribute by Edward R. Royball, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Awards and Honors: "The Liberators" tribute dinner, Simon Wiesenthal Center, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Awards and Honors: Commendation from Ronald Reagan, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Awards and Honors: Decoration of Merit in Gold, Die Wiener Landesregierung, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Awards and Honors: National Tribute Dinner, Simon Wiesenthal Center, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Awards and Honors: other awards and honors, 1984-1987 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Newsclippings: Articles from Der Judenstaat, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Newsclippings, 1960-1969 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Newsclippings, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Newsclippings, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Newsclippings, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Newsclippings, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Newsclippings, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Newsclippings:, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Newsclippings, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Newsclippings, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Newsclippings, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Newsclippings, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Newsclippings, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Newsclippings, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Newsclippings, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Newsclippings, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Newsclippings, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Newsclippings, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Newsclippings, 1990-1998 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Military service files, 1941-1968; MS2026 Series 3; 1 Linear foot
  The Military Service Files consist of correspondence and records relating to William R. Perl's service in the United States Army. Documents date from 1941 to 1968 (bulk 1941-1949). The Military Service Files are divided into two groups: Military Services Records and Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files. Documents in this series are grouped by topic, with folders arranged chronologically. Researchers using this series should consult the Mixed Media series for related photographs.
  The Military Service Records materials (2 folders) contains copies and originals of William R. Perl's United States Army service records, dating from 1941 to 1968.
  The Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files materials (approx. 1 cubic foot) documents the proceedings and subsequent Senate investigation of the war crimes trial of German soldiers who participated in the killing of American soldiers in Malmedy, Belgium (1944). The files are divided into Affidavits and Correspondence and Other Materials. The Affidavits materials consists of copies of affidavits written in 1945 and 1946 by Germans who participated in or witnessed the massacre. Some original affidavits are included. Nearly all affidavits are handwritten in German, though occasionally a typewritten English translation is included. Related correspondence, clippings and other materials are filed at the end of this grouping in the Correspondence and Other Materials group.
  - Military Service Records, 1941-1948 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Military Service Records, 1952-1968 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Christ, Friedrich, 1945 December 17 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Wichmann, Otto, 1945 December 28 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Fleps, Georg, 1946 January 01 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Siptrett, Hans, 1946 January 07 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [untified], 1946 January 09 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [untified], 1946 January 22 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Sprenger, Gustav Adolf, 1946 January 23 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Wichmann, Otto, 1946 January 23 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Kotzur, Georg, 1946 January 31 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [untified], 1946 January 31 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Zwigart, Paul, 1946 February 11 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [untified], 1946 February 16 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Sievers, Franz, 1946 February 25 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Rodenburg, Axel, 1946 February 26 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Sievers, Franz, 1946 February 27 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Junker, Benoni, 1946 March 01 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Hofman, Joachim, 1946 March 06 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Neve, Sturmann Gustav, 1946 March 06 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Tomhardt, Heinz, 1946 March 06 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Szyperski, Erwin, 1946 March 07 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Rehagel, Heinz, 1946 March 08 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Szyperski, Erwin, 1946 March 08 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Rau, Fritz, 1946 March 12 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Godicke, Heinz, 1946 March 13 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Hennecke, Hans, 1946 March 13 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Ritzer, Rolf, 1946 March 13 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Hecht, Armin, 1946 March 14 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Hillig, Hans, 1946 March 15 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Hofman, Heinz, 1946 March 15 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Klingelhoefer, Oskar, 1946 March 15 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Stock, Herbert, 1946 March 15 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Gruhle, Hans Erich, 1946 March 18 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Klingelhoefer, Oskar, 1946 March 18 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Reiser, Rolf Roland, 1946 March 20 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: von Chamier, Willi, 1946 March 21 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Friedrichs, Heinz, 1946 March 21 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Peiper, Joachim, 1946 March 21 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Dietrich, Joseph (Sepp), 1946 March 22 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Rumpf, Erich, 1946 March 22 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Sternebeck, Werner, 1946 March 23 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Kies, Friedel, 1946 March 26 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Rieder, Max, 1946 March 26 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [unidentified], 1946 March 26 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Sternebeck, Werner, 1946 March 27 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Tomczak, Edmund, 1946 March 27 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Bersin, Valentin, 1946 March 30 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Goldschmidt, Ernst, 1946 March 30 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Kuhn, Werner, 1946 March 30 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Fischer, Arndt, 1946 March 31 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Hecht, Armin, 1946 April 01 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Hendel, Willi Heinz, 1946 April 04 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Siegmund, Oswald, 1946 April 04 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Hendel, Willi Heinz, 1946 April 05 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [unidentified], 1946 April 05 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Peiper, Joachim, 1946 April 08 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Pletz, Hans, 1946 April 08 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Schaefer, Willi, 1946 April 08 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Schambach, Rudolf, 1946 April 08 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Kraemer, Fritz, 1946 April 10 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Bode, Friedel, 1946 April 12 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Weis, Gunther, 1946 April 12 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Coblenz, Manfred, 1946 April 15 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Braun, Willi, 1946 April 16 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Priess, Hermann, 1946 April 16 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Richter, Wolfgang, 1946 April 16 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Wasenberger, Johann, 1946 April 16 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Hendel, Heinz, 1946 April 18 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Clotten, Roman, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Freimuth, Arvid, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Jakel, Siegfried, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Ochmann, Paul, undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Rumpf, Erich, undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: Sickel, Kurt, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [unidentified], undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [unidentified], undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [unidentified], undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [unidentified], undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [unidentified], undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [unidentified], undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [unidentified], undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [unidentified], undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [unidentified], undated (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [unidentified], undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [unidentified], undated (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [unidentified], undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [unidentified], undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [unidentified], undated (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [unidentified], undated (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [unidentified], undated (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [unidentified], undated (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [unidentified], undated (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [unidentified], undated (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [unidentified], undated (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [unidentified], undated (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [unidentified], undated (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [unidentified], undated (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [unidentified], undated (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [unidentified], undated (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [unidentified], undated (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [unidentified], undated (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [unidentified], undated (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [unidentified], undated (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [unidentified], undated (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Affidavits: [unidentified], undated (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Correspondence and Other Materials: Miscellaneous notes, memoranda and records, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Correspondence and Other Materials: Correspondence, statements and notes regarding Senate investigation, 1948-1961 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Correspondence and Other Materials: Correspondence with Danny S. Parker, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Correspondence and Other Materials: Writings by WRP about Malmedy, undated (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Malmedy War Crimes Trial Files: Correspondence and Other Materials: Newsclippings, 1949-1976 (Box 6, Folder 60)
- Professional files, 1940-1968; MS2026 Series 4; 0.25 Linear feet
  The Professional Files series consists of 49 folders of materials documenting William R. Perl's work as a psychologist. Recurring themes in the documentation are Perl's work as a handwriting analyst (1940s-50s) and his examination of the Boys Training School in Kearney, Nebraska (1968). There are six groups within the Professional Files series including: Writings; Speeches and Statements; Syllabi and Course Materials; Certification, Workshops and Conferences; Correspondence; and Newsclippings. Unless otherwise noted, documents in this series are grouped together by topic, with folders arranged chronologically.
  The Writings materials consists of 21 folders of journal and newsletter articles on psychological topics written by William R. Perl, along with related correspondence. Materials in this sub-series date from 1952 to 1968, with some items not dated.
  The Speeches and Statements materials contain 9 folders documenting Perl's participation in lectures, interviews and other oral explications of his professional work (1942-1968, bulk 1968). In some cases, only a program, letter, or other ephemeral document is available.
  The Syllabi and Course Materials materials (3 folders) contains evidence of university courses taught by William R. Perl from 1960 to 1967, including syllabi, a quiz, and other items.
  The Certifications, Workshops and Conferences materials (7 folders) documents other professional Perl's professional activities outside of his place of work. This group contains programs, correspondence, certificates, and other items dating 1951-1968.
  The Correspondence (8 folders) consists of letters and related materials dating from 1942 to 1976. Notable within the Correspondence series are several letters from the artist Rockwell Kent, who was interested in Perl's methods of handwriting analysis. Folders in this sub-series are arranged alphabetically by last name of the correspondent.
  The Newsclippings consist of one folder with materials dating 1948-1968, with the bulk of clippings dating from 1968. The majority of the clippings concern Perl's work with the Kearney, Nebraska Boy's Training School.
  - Writings: "Your Chance to Speak Up." A Psychological Forum, 1952 October (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Writings: [Book review of] "Out of Step by Joseph Trenaman." Military Review. v.33:no.6, 1953 September (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Writings: "Motivation and Delinquency of Miliary Volunteers and Draftees." Training Analysis and Development Information Bulletin. v.4:no.4:Win., 1953 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Writings: "Military Delinquency and Service Motivation." Military Review. v.33:no.10, 1954 January (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Writings: "O Crime Militar e a Motivacao para o Servico." Military Review Edicao Brasileira. v.33:no.10, 1954 January (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Writings: "Utilization in Group Therapy of Disadvantages of the Prevailing Prison System." Group Psychology. v.7:no.2, 1954 October (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Writings: "On the Psychodiagnostic Value of Handwriting Analysis." American Journal of Psychiatry. v.3:no.8, 1955 February (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Writings: "Benefits from Including One Psychopath in a Group of Mildly Delinquent Patients." International Journal of Group Therapy. v.6:no.1, 1956 January (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Writings: "Therapeutic Use of Certaifects of the Usual Prison." Journal of Criminal Law, Criminology and Political Science. v.47:no.1, 1956 May-1956 June (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Writings: "American Communities in Foreign Settings: Group Problems and an American Family Group Therapy Programme in Germany." The International Journal of Social Psychology. v.3:no.4 Spr.), 1958 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Writings: "On the Psychodiagnostic Value of Handwriting Analysis." Mededelingen van het College van Beheerdersva Stichting Orde van Practiserende Graphologen. v.4:no.3/4, 1959 October - November (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Writings: "Group Psychotherapy at the Children's Center." The Director's Newsletter. v.3:no.4, 1960 April (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Writings: "Use of Fantasy for a Breakthrough in Psychotherapy Groups of Hard-to-Reach Delinquent Boys." International Journal of Group Psychotherapy. v.13:no.1, 1963 January (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Writings: "An Autogenic Jury of Disturbed Delinquent Children: A Study in Institutional Self-Government." Corrective Psychiatry and Journal of Social Therapy. v.9:no.3, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Writings: "The Quiet Child." School Health News Notes. no.81 Spr., 1965 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Writings: "Graphic Demonstration of Receding Schizophrenia." Archives of General Psychiatry. v.14, 1966 January (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Writings: "Intermediate Report of the [State of Nebraska] Legislature Council Committee on the Increase in Crime Rate.", 1968 July 01 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Writings: "Report of the Nebraska Legislative Council Committee on Increase in Crime Rate." Committee Report no. 174, 1968 December (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Writings: "Look Up While You Work.", undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Writings: "What Is Good About Our Prisons.", undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Writings: "Character Detective.", undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Speeches and Statements: "Your Personality in Handwriting,", 1948 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Speeches and Statements: "Military Delinquency and the Problem of Motivation for Military Service in American Culture,", 1953 October 08 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Speeches and Statements: Lectures at University of Kansas Medical Center, 1955 April 02 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Speeches and Statements: "Violence in the United States," ZOA House, 1968 August 12 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Speeches and Statements: "The Changing Family in America," Annual Institute of Social Work, 1968 October 17 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Speeches and Statements: Interview for Center News and Views, v.6:no.1, 1968 January-February (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Speeches and Statements: Speech before the Nebraska Welfare Association, 1968 November 12 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Speeches and Statements: "The Trail You Leave in Ink,", undated (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Speeches and Statements: Correspondence regarding other speeches and statements, 1942-1958 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Syllabi and Course Materials: Courses taught, 1960-1964 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Syllabi and Course Materials: "Problems in Human Adjustment,", 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Syllabi and Course Materials: "Psychology of Family Relationships,", undated (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Certification, Workshops and Conferences: Board certification, 1951-1980 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Certification, Workshops and Conferences: Mid-continent Psychiatric Association Annual Meeting, 1953 March 28-29 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Certification, Workshops and Conferences: White House Conference on Children and Youth, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Certification, Workshops and Conferences: "Conference on Mental Retardation,", 1961 November 09 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Certification, Workshops and Conferences: National Institute on Crime and Delinquency, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Certification, Workshops and Conferences: District of Columbia Psychological Association, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Certification, Workshops and Conferences: American Academy of Political and Social Science, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence: Barr, William, 1968 February 23 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence: Bourne, Leo Joel, 1966 April 16 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence: Letter from WRP to unknown correspondent, 1967 January 25 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence: Donner, Laurence, 1976 February 13 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence: Eisen, David, undated (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence: Haynes, Henry W., 1942 July 16 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence: Kent, Rockwell, 1943-1952 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence: Thompson, Winifred G., 1958 July 24 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Newsclippings, 1948-1968 (Box 7, Folder 49)
- Legal files, 1974-1979; MS2026 Series 5; 0.25 Linear feet